Hello, everyone.
大家好。
So welcome to the nice lecture.
欢迎来到这个精彩的讲座。
This lecture, it's the content of this lecture.
这节课，是关于这节课的内容。
It's included in your first meter.
这已经包含在您的第一个计量单位中。
That's quite important.
这非常重要。
It's also a very important lecture for your future homeworks and projects.
这也是对你未来的作业和项目非常重要的一堂课。
So,
所以，
and we are going to continue our discussion about abstraction to implement critical
我们将继续讨论关于实现关键抽象的问题。
sections and synchronization between processes.
进程间的分段和同步。
If you remember,
如果你还记得的话，
last time we discussed that one of the main abstraction,
上次我们讨论了一个主要的抽象概念，
which it makes it easier to implement critical sections,
这使得实现临界区更加容易。
exclusion from critical sections.
临界区的排除
So only one thread it should be active in a critical section
在关键区域中只能有一个线程处于活动状态。
at a given time or locks.
在给定的时间或锁定状态下。
And we discuss the implementation of locks using interrupts.
我们讨论了使用中断实现锁的方法。
And then we said there are some disadvantages of using interacts and some dangers.
然后我们说使用交互式界面存在一些缺点和一些危险性。
And then we discuss about,
然后我们讨论关于...
then using atomic operation,
然后使用原子操作，
which are more sophisticated than load and store to implement these locks.
相比于加载和存储操作，有更复杂的方法来实现这些锁。
And one of them,
其中之一，
it will be like best and set.
它将会像最好和设置一样。
I if you remember,
如果你还记得的话，
is a test and set,
是一个测试和设置操作。
it's takes a value
它接受一个值。
and maintains a local variable.
并且维护一个本地变量。
Think about distance that maintains a local variable.
考虑一下维持局部变量的距离。
The atomic operation is that taking a value,
原子操作是指获取一个值，
updating the local variable is a new value,
更新本地变量为一个新值。
and then returning the previous value of the local variable.
然后返回局部变量的先前值。
That's pretty much.
就是这样。
This is and implementation.
这是一个实现。
Again, we discussed last time of a lock acquire and lock release and
上次我们讨论了锁的获取和释放问题，
using test and set,
使用测试和设置（test and set）操作，
and basically use test and set here also to implement mutual
在这里，基本上也可以使用测试和设置来实现互斥。
exclusion are of operating of the is the value of the lock.
互斥是操作系统中锁的一个重要属性。
The lock,
锁定，
value of the lock, which whereas is busy or free,
锁的值，无论是忙碌还是空闲，
determine whether you can enter or not in the critical section
确定你是否可以进入临界区
of the program of the user.
用户程序的功能。
Now we have a second,
现在我们有第二个
we use test and set for a second smaller critical section,
我们使用测试并设置（test and set）来实现一个较小的临界区。
which is only concern of updating the lock value to be your free.
这只涉及将锁的值更新为可用的问题。
If you remember,
如果你还记得的话，
all these synchronization primitives involves weight,
所有这些同步原语都涉及到权重。
the reason for that is because it's fundamental because if you have
这是因为这是基本的原因，如果你有的话。
two threads which wants to enter in the same critical section,
两个线程想要进入同一个临界区
you can only allow one thread to enter in the critical section.
你只允许一个线程进入临界区。
Therefore, the other thread has nothing else to do,
因此，另一个线程没有其他事情要做。
but wait for the first step to finish.
但是请等待第一步完成。
So that's why waiting is fundamental.
这就是为什么等待是基本的。
Okay?
好的？
The other thing you remember,
你还记得的另一件事是，
if you wait one way to wait,
如果你等待一种方式来等待，
it's easy to implement the still busy waiting.
实现静态忙等待很容易。
You constantly check whether the critical section is free,
你不断地检查临界区是否空闲，
whether you can acquire the lock.
你是否能够获取锁。
But this consumes the cpu cycles without doing any useful work.
但这样会消耗 CPU 周期而没有做任何有用的工作。
So therefore,
因此，
waiting, what you want to invent,
等待中，你想要发明什么？
the best way to implement,
最佳实现方式是，
waiting and the preferred way is to go to sleep,
等待的最佳方式是进入睡眠状态，
to put the thread when the waiting queue,
将线程放入等待队列中
and then to be open up when there are the previous thread exceeds
当前线程超过之前的线程时，就会打开。
the critical section.
临界区。
Okay?
好的？
This is what you see here.
这是你在这里看到的。
If the value is busy,
如果值忙碌，
if someone acquired a lock and has acquired a locker in the critical section,
如果有人获取了一个锁，并且在临界区中获取了一个储物柜，
you put the thread on the weight queue,
你将线程放入了权重队列中。
and then you go to sleep,
然后你去睡觉，
and then you reset this card, which is, again,
然后你重新设置这张卡片，这又是
this card it's about.
这张卡片是关于什么的。
It's basically you freeze a lock for the critical section,
这基本上是将一个锁冻结以保护临界区。
which is concerned with updating the busy value.
这个问题涉及到更新繁忙值。
As it's the value is busy,
由于该值正忙，请稍后再试。
you set the value to be,
你将值设置为，
this requires a lock,
这需要一个锁。
then you again, said,
那么你又说，
go out to zero.
出发前往零点。
So that for you are going to allow another thread to look,
所以你要允许另一个线程来查看
tend to read the log value and modify it.
倾向于读取日志值并进行修改。
Any questions here?
这里有什么问题吗？
So not, again, that we have the same discussion.
所以，不要再次讨论这个问题了。
We have the same discussion like in the in the case of when using interrupt
我们的讨论与在使用中断时的情况类似。
to implement the choir and release.
实现合唱和发布。
And that is is when we are going to set the guard to zero,
这就是我们要将警卫设置为零的时候，
there is one you are going to disable the interact.
你要禁用交互的一个功能。
And this needs to be done.
这个需要完成。
You cannot do before sleep,
睡觉前不能做。
you cannot do before the thread on weight queue.
在权重队列上的线程之前，你不能这样做。
Just remember.
请记住。
Why is that?
为什么这样做呢？
You can look at the last lecture.
你可以查看上一堂课的讲义。
So you need to do, in some sense, after,
在某种意义上，你需要在之后做一些事情。
but then after the thread itself,
但在线程本身之后，
which call acquire cannot do it because it's sleeping.
由于它正在休眠，调用acquire无法执行。
So that has to be done either by the operating system or by the next trend,
这要么由操作系统完成，要么由下一个趋势完成。
which is going to be scheduled to reset the guard.
将被安排重置警卫。
Okay?
好的？
Here it's a simple example.
这是一个简单的例子。
This is a great question.
这是一个很好的问题。
So one question here, it was a the guard and value will be on the hip.
这里有一个问题，它是关于警卫和价值物品放在腰间的。
They are going to be on.
它们即将开启。
They're going to be a global variables,
它们将成为全局变量。
so everyone can access them.
这样每个人都可以访问它们。
Now,
现在，
we've seen two implementation is actually of acquire and release locks.
我们已经看到了两种实现实际上是获取和释放锁的方式。
One is using interacts,
一种方法是使用交互式操作。
and the other one using test and set.
另一个方法使用测试和设置。
And this basically shows is to show you that actually the logic is very,
这基本上是要向您展示的是实际上逻辑非常简单，
very similar.
非常相似。
And you can think about while test and set,
你可以在测试和设置时考虑一下，
it's similarly disabled interrupts and enabling and guard a reseting guard
类似地，禁用中断并启用和保护复位保护。
to zero is like enabling the interacts.
将其归零就像启用交互功能。
This is against the code for we went over last lecture about implementing,
这违反了我们上一堂关于实现的课程中讲到的规范。
acquire,
获取、获得、取得
and release by disabling and enabling the internet.
通过禁用和启用互联网来释放。
And if you remember,
如果你还记得的话，
also what they did last time,
还有上次他们做了什么？
when we talk about locks we did in two stages.
当我们谈论锁时，我们分为两个阶段进行。
First of all,
首先，
we said we gave this very trivial implementation of the locks acquire.
我们说过我们给出了这个非常简单的锁获取的实现。
You disable the interrupts,
你禁用了中断。
why it is able to interrupt,
为什么它能够中断？
because you don't want new new threats to interrupt you, right?
因为你不想让新的威胁打断你，对吗？
While you are in the critical section, right?
你是指在临界区域内吗？
And then the release is enabling the internet.
然后发布将使互联网变得可用。
But this was very dangerous because if you call as the user level,
但这样做非常危险，因为如果你在用户级别下调用，
acquiring, disable, interrupts,
获取，禁用，中断
and you have a very long critical section or you make mistakes and you have
一个很长的临界区或者你犯了错误，并且你有
an infinite while loop in the critical section.
在临界区中有一个无限循环。
Then your computer will hack.
那么你的计算机将被黑客攻击。
You can do anything about.
你可以对此事做任何事情。
The only thing probably is power off power on.
可能的唯一解决办法就是关机重启。
Right?
对吗？
So therefore,
因此，
is a more sophisticated implementation was to use disable and enable
更复杂的实现方式是使用禁用和启用。
interrupts only for updating the value of the lock.
中断仅用于更新锁的值。
Now you have a value of the lock which set to zero and you disable
现在你有一个值为零的锁，并且你已经禁用了它。
and enable interrupts to update that value,
并启用中断来更新该值，
right?
对的？
Or to leave that value.
或者保留该值。
Now you still use disable and enable interacts.
现在你仍然使用禁用和启用交互。
But now it's very short.
但现在很短。
The critical section is very short and is going to finish very fast.
临界区非常短，将会非常快地完成。
Right?
对吗？
If you look,
如果你看一下，
again, if you look now at the same example,
再次，如果你现在看同一个例子，
but now implementing, acquire, and release,
但现在正在实现、获取和释放。
using test and set,
使用测试和设置（test and set）操作，
we went again through two iterations.
我们又进行了两轮迭代。
The first iteration was very simple that while distance set values,
第一次迭代非常简单，只是在距离设置值时。
you are doing the values, a lot of value.
你正在做一些有价值的事情，很多价值。
While this is why the value is one.
这就是为什么值为一的原因。
Right?
对吗？
Again, the distance said here,
这里再次提到的距离
if value is one,
如果值为一，
is going to returns the previous value of the internal variable
将返回内部变量的先前值
of test and set,
测试并设置
and then set that variable to the new value.
然后将该变量设置为新值。
If it's the previous one was zero, returned,
如果前一个是零，则返回。
zero means there's a lock.
zero 表示有锁。
It's acquired.
已获取。
But now he said to one next time,
但是现在他对下一次说道，
when someone tries,
当有人尝试时，
the value is one,
这个值是一。
the internal variable is one.
内部变量为一。
The internal variables will not change.
内部变量不会改变。
And the test and said returns once you are going to be stuck in the white group.
当测试和返回一次时，你将会被困在白色组中。
Okay?
好的？
But it's, again, the problem is this one,
但是，问题又回到了这个。
and the release is simply set the value to zero.
而释放操作只是将值设置为零。
And the problem with this one,
这个的问题是，
remember this while, look,
记住这一点，看着，
again, it's like it's busy waiting.
再次，就好像它在忙等待一样。
I which we discuss that you want to wait, we want to, sorry,
我认为我们应该讨论一下你想要等待的事情，我们也想要，抱歉。
it's busy waiting.
它正在忙等待。
You should remember we want to avoid.
你应该记住我们想要避免的事情。
Right.
好的。
Again, in this case,
同样，在这种情况下，
we went to the second iteration,
我们进入了第二次迭代。
which we just also presented again,
我们刚刚也再次呈现了。
earlier in the lecture, today's lecture.
在之前的讲座中，今天的讲座。
And you use the test and set only to protect the critical sections,
你只需要使用测试和设置（test and set）来保护临界区。
which are concerned with updating the value of the lock.
涉及更新锁的值的操作。
Now, again, this is much shorter,
现在，再次，这个要短得多，
critical section.
临界区
The test and set will be,
测试并设置
will you wait only for a very short time?
你只能等待很短的时间吗？
And now,
现在，
instead of like, in this case,
在这种情况下，不是像这样，而是
you wait pink, you are waiting.
你等一下，你正在等待。
In the previous case, you are waiting.
在之前的情况下，你正在等待。
As long as someone is in the critical section, do busy waiting.
只要有人在临界区内，就进行忙等待。
So constraints as if you cycles.
所以约束条件就像是循环一样。
In this case,
在这种情况下，
in the more refined iteration,
在更精细的迭代中，
you are going to put the thread which is waiting on the wake you.
你将把等待唤醒的线程放入其中。
Right?
对吗？
So there is no busy waiting.
所以没有忙等待。
Any questions here?
这里有什么问题吗？
So what we are going again with synchronization?
我们再次讨论同步问题吗？
So let's see what we've done.
那么让我们来看看我们已经做了什么。
We look on the hardware support.
我们关注硬件支持。
The love stores is able to interrupt test and set and compare and swap.
这个锁能够中断测试和设置以及比较和交换操作。
These are similar contest and set and compare and swap.
这些是类似的竞赛、集合和比较交换操作。
They are much more useful than load and store.
它们比加载和存储更加有用。
And we saw how you can't use these to implement locks.
我们看到了你不能使用这些来实现锁。
And also he discusses abstraction about singapore's.
他还讨论了关于新加坡的抽象概念。
And and then next also like that,
然后接下来也是这样的，
we are going to talk about monitors.
我们将要讨论关于监视器的话题。
It's, again, the higher level,
又是高层次的问题，
the abstraction, the easier will be for the programs,
抽象化程度越高，程序编写就会变得更加容易。
for the application to implement mutual exclusion and critical sections.
为应用程序实现互斥和临界区。
Next, we are going to go and talk more about this abstraction.
接下来，我们将进一步讨论这个抽象概念。
Let's talk again about summer force that, right?
让我们再次谈谈关于夏季的力量，对吗？
And if you remember,
如果你还记得的话，
just to remind you the summer force,
只是提醒你夏季的力量。
you have that a little bit more sophisticated than locks.
你需要的是比锁更复杂一点的东西。
A lock can have only two values,
一个锁只能有两个值，
01, or busy and three.
01，或者忙碌和三。
We summer force is like a counter,
我们的夏季力量就像一个计数器，
write a special counter,
编写一个特殊的计数器。
like you have a primitive which increments the summer
就像你有一个原始操作，可以将夏天的值增加一样。
for and a primitive decline as a summer for.
为了和一个原始的下降作为夏天。
Then if sum of four is zero,
那么如果四个数的和为零，
then you are going to wait that you are very much.
那你要等很久了。
You are waiting for a lock,
你正在等待一个锁。
which is busy,
哪个正在忙？
if you remember.
如果你记得的话。
So that provides you a little bit more,
这样可以为你提供更多信息，
a little bit more power.
稍微多一点功率。
And therefore,
因此，
it also gives you more,
它还能给你更多，
if gives you more functionality,
如果提供更多功能，
you can implement with the summer for both critical sections.
你可以为两个临界区都实现一个夏令时。
But you also implement and material exclusion,
但你还要实施和物质排斥。
but you also implement can scheduling constraints basically telling
但你还可以实现调度约束，基本上是在告诉计算机操作系统如何进行调度。
signaling one approach a process
信号量是一种进程间通信的方法。
from another process or a threat from another threat.
来自另一个进程或来自另一个线程的威胁。
If you remember,
如果你还记得的话，
the example we gave last time about this was about,
我们上次给出的关于这个的例子是关于...
if you remember,
如果你记得的话，
it was about implementing the strategy,
这是关于实施策略的事情。
waiting the thread who launches a create another thread,
等待启动一个创建另一个线程的线程。
waiting for the new creative,
等待新的创意。
for the greatest thread to finish.
为了让最重要的线程完成。
Right?
对吗？
It's again.
又是你。
Now, we are going to move from locks and some efforts to a new abstraction,
现在，我们将从锁和一些努力转向一个新的抽象概念，
which is called monitors.
这被称为监视器。
And monitors are better,
而且显示器更好，
are simply more powerful.
更加强大。
And and the main idea is to split between and
主要的想法是在之间进行分割。
supporting explicitly these two functionality
明确支持这两个功能
about mark mutual exclusion and scheduling constraints.
关于标记互斥和调度约束。
You use locks for mutual exclusion and what are called condition variable
你可以使用锁来实现互斥，并且还可以使用条件变量。
for scheduling constraints,
对于调度约束，
right?
对的？
A monitor.
一个显示器。
It's a lock and a zero or more conditional variable for managing
这是一个用于管理锁和一个或多个条件变量的机制。
concurrent access to share that.
并发访问共享资源。
And we'll talk more about that.
我们将会更详细地讨论这个问题。
Some languages provide this negatively.
有些语言提供了这个功能的否定形式。
And most of the others,
还有大部分其他的人，
you can use lock and conditional variables as a distinct abstractions.
你可以使用锁和条件变量作为独立的抽象。
I'm going again,
我要再走一次，
if you have any questions,
如果你有任何问题，
let me know this is, again,
请再次告诉我这是什么。
these lectures,
这些讲座，
the past lecture in these lectures are not very easy to follow,
这些讲座中的过去一节并不容易理解。
because they are about concurrency,
因为它们涉及并发性，
are about programs which execute come correctly.
是关于程序正确执行的问题。
And like we discussed last time,
正如我们上次讨论的那样，
it's we,
这是我们。
as humans are not very used about handling many things which happen
由于人类并不习惯处理许多事情的发生
at the same time.
同时。
We had much better in equalizing sequentializing things.
我们在使事物变得相等和顺序化方面做得更好。
So it's perfectly fine.
所以这是完全没问题的。
I if you feel this is a little bit more challenging,
如果你觉得这有点更具挑战性，
but at the same time,
但与此同时，
this also means that you should spend a little bit more time
这也意味着你应该多花一点时间。
to try to understand deeply what's happening here.
努力深入理解这里发生的事情。
Again, some languages provide monitors.
再次强调，一些编程语言提供了监视器。
And let's see what is conditional variables,
让我们来看看什么是条件变量。
conditional variables,
条件变量
what is a conditional variable?
条件变量是一种在多线程编程中使用的同步机制。它允许线程在满足特定条件之前等待，并在条件满足时被唤醒。条件变量通常与互斥锁一起使用，以确保线程在访问共享资源之前等待正确的条件。当条件不满足时，线程会进入等待状态，释放互斥锁，直到其他线程通过唤醒操作通知条件变量满足条件为止。一旦条件满足，线程会重新获得互斥锁，并继续执行。条件变量的使用可以有效地避免线程的忙等待，提高多线程程序的效率。
It's a queue of threads waiting for something inside a critical section to happen.
这是一个等待在关键区域内某些事件发生的线程队列。
And the nice thing about the critical section send the conditional,
关于临界区和条件发送的好处是，
sorry,
对不起，
and I think about the monitors and conditional variables is conditional variables,
我认为你在谈论监视器和条件变量，其中条件变量是一种条件变量。
allow sleeping inside the critical section by atomically,
通过原子操作允许在临界区内休眠。
releasing the lock at a time regardlessly.
无论何时都会释放锁定。
So what I mean by that,
所以我的意思是，
here is what I mean.
这是我的意思。
Remember about this slide?
还记得这张幻灯片吗？
I'll go soon in again in presentation mode.
我很快会再次进入演示模式。
Here,
在这里，
it's a game.
这是一个游戏。
If you try to acquire the lock,
如果你尝试获取锁定，
and the lock is busy,
锁已被占用，
so the value is one.
所以这个值是一。
You have to go to sleep.
你必须去睡觉。
And what you want,
你想要什么？
we want this,
我们想要这个。
how we want this to happen is to put the thread in the waiting queue.
我们希望的做法是将线程放入等待队列中。
But when you put the set of the waiting queue,
但是当你将等待队列的集合放入时，
you need also to really to resell the guard To let other threads.
你还需要确保重新放置守卫，以允许其他线程进入。
And there is a critical section to look at the value,
并且有一个关键部分需要查看该值，
maybe to modify the value.
可能是为了修改这个值。
So now the sleep and the guard have to happen at the same time.
现在，睡眠和保护必须同时发生。
Okay?
好的？
They need to be atomic and monitors,
它们需要是原子操作和监视器。
provide and conditional variables for monitors.
为监视器提供条件变量和条件变量。
条件变量是一种同步机制，用于在多个线程之间进行通信和协调。它们通常与锁结合使用，以确保线程在满足特定条件之前等待，并在条件满足时被唤醒。
在监视器中，条件变量用于在共享资源的状态发生变化时通知等待线程。它们允许线程在等待条件满足时进入休眠状态，并在条件满足时被唤醒。
提供变量用于监视器的实现。它们用于控制对共享资源的访问，并确保线程按照特定的顺序执行。提供变量通常与锁结合使用，以确保线程在访问共享资源之前获取锁，并在完成后释放锁。
通过使用条件变量和提供变量，可以实现线程之间的协调和同步，以避免竞争条件和死锁等问题。这些机制是操作系统中重要的工具，用于实现并发和并行程序的正确性和效率。
Provide you this atomicity between the threads going to sleep and giving
确保线程进入睡眠和释放之间的原子性
up releasing the lock,
释放锁
because it's equally zero release a clock associated with a guard atomically.
因为它等于零，所以原子地释放与保护原子关联的时钟。
You don't need to worry about that.
你不需要担心那个。
That's what conditional variables in monitors are going to do for you.
这就是在监视器中使用条件变量所能为你做的事情。
And that's why they are very useful.
这就是为什么它们非常有用。
Here are the operations,
以下是操作列表：
the operation you wait for the lock,
你等待锁的操作
which I thought you can you can automatically,
我以为你可以自动完成这个任务。
this is going to,
这将要
the operation is going to automatically leads a lock and go to sleep.
该操作将自动获取锁并进入休眠状态。
You can acquire the lock like that.
你可以这样获取锁。
Will also have a few examples to make it more understandable.
还会有一些例子，以使其更易理解。
Then you have signals.
然后你有信号。
You remember that one of the use of the summer force was to signal when one,
你还记得夏季力的一个用途是用来指示何时有一个
a thread, one,
一个线程
an event right between two threads.
两个线程之间的事件。
So now you have a very primitive,
现在你有一个非常原始的，
which is called makes a lot of sense.
这个被称为的确很有道理。
A name is signal.
一个名字是一个信号。
You have also something which is called broadcast,
你还有一种叫做广播的东西，
the signal,
信号
its way, its waking,
它的方式，它的觉醒，
a thread, which is waiting for some particular event to happen,
一个线程，它正在等待某个特定事件的发生，
broadcasts,
广播
its waking multiple waiters,
它正在唤醒多个等待者，
all the waiters, which run,
所有正在运行的服务员，
which waits for the people.
等待着人们的地方。
Signal, if there are multiple waiters,
如果有多个等待者，就发送信号。
it's going to wake only one.
只会唤醒一个。
And that's non deterministic.
这是非确定性的。
You don't know which one is going to be waking up.
你不知道哪一个会被唤醒。
And in many cases, you don't care.
在许多情况下，你并不在意。
Broadcast wakes all of them.
广播会唤醒它们中的所有进程。
Okay.
好的。
Now, when you do that,
现在，当你这样做时，
when you do operation on the condition variables,
当你对条件变量进行操作时，
you need to own the lock.
你需要拥有锁。
Right?
对吗？
Because this is in critical section.
因为这是在临界区。
This is one way to represent it.
这是一种表示方法。
The monikers,
这些别名，
x and y are conditional variables.
x和y是条件变量。
Each of them is associated acute.
每个都与急性相关。
And you have a log,
你有一个日志文件，
which provides a mutual exclusion with a shared data.
这个提供了对共享数据的互斥访问。
In this monitor.
在这个监视器中。
The conditional variables are shared it.
条件变量是共享的。
But it's, again,
但是，再一次，
one of the main advantage you are allowed to wait in the critical section.
你被允许在临界区等待是其中一个主要的优势。
This is not allowed for summer force,
这对于暑期强制工作是不允许的。
which makes the summer falls very,
这使得夏天变得非常炎热
how much harder to use.
使用起来有多困难？
Now, it's, again, let's see.
现在，再次，让我们看看。
And we are going to have a lot of examples.
我们将会有很多例子。
So we give you a better sense about how these monitors,
这样我们可以更好地了解这些显示器，
how you use the monitors.
如何使用监视器。
And also we are going to talk about how they are implemented.
我们还将讨论它们是如何实现的。
Hopefully, by the end of these lectures,
希望在这些讲座结束时，
we are going to have a pretty good feeling about monitors.
我们对显示器的感觉会非常好。
Okay.
好的。
Here is an infinite cube, single eyes.
这是一个无限立方体，只有一个眼睛。
You got producer, consumer.
你有生产者和消费者。
It's infinite in the sense that the producer can put any numbers of items
从生产者的角度来看，它是无限的，因为生产者可以放置任意数量的物品。
in the queue is infinite.
队列是无限的。
How do you do it?
你是如何做到的？
The producer is like your choir is a lock.
生产者就像你的合唱团是一个锁。
It really is a lock.
这真的是一个锁。
You have a buffer lock,
你有一个缓冲区锁。
and the consumer also acquired the lock and release a lock.
消费者也获得了锁并释放了锁。
Right?
对吗？
This is in order to protect the critical sections which are operating
这是为了保护正在运行的临界区。
on the queue.
在队列中。
Right?
对吗？
You don't want a producer and the consumer to operate on the cure
你不希望生产者和消费者在同一个资源上操作
at the same time.
同时。
Because inserting adding a new element to the queue,
因为要向队列中插入一个新元素，
removing an element from the queue are not atomic operations.
从队列中移除一个元素不是原子操作。
Therefore,
因此，
bad things can happen while you both of them are manipulating the pointers,
在两个人同时操作指针时，可能会发生不好的事情。
right?
对的？
To insert or remove the element from the queue.
向队列中插入或移除元素。
Now, you need to you,
现在，你需要你自己。
you can use these conditioned variables like buff cv
你可以像使用 buff cv 一样使用这些条件变量。
in order to signal the producer.
为了通知生产者。
That's basically what says.
基本上就是这样说的。
The buff cv is a signal,
缓冲区（buff）是一种信号。
a is a way for the producer to signal the consumer that there are elements
a 是生产者向消费者发出信号，表示有元素可用。
in the buffer in the queue.
在队列中的缓冲区中。
This is what it is, your signal.
这就是它，你的信号。
It what do you do from in the consumer?
你在消费者中做什么工作？
While it's empty?
在它是空的时候吗？
So you look for the cure as it's empty.
所以你正在寻找治愈，因为它是空的。
Right?
对吗？
It's in the critical section,
它处于临界区。
so it's far as fair to look at the queue,
所以看待队列是公平的。
because no one else will modify the queue while you are
因为在你操作队列时，没有其他人会对其进行修改。
in the critical section to operate on the queue.
在临界区操作队列。
And then you call this condition, wait.
然后你将这个条件称为等待。
So you're waiting for this signal for the best subsidy.
所以你正在等待这个信号来获得最佳的补贴。
And you also, you see,
而且你也明白，
this is the first argument of condition weight.
这是条件权重的第一个参数。
And the second argument in buffalo, why is that?
在buffalo中的第二个参数是为什么？
Because if the queue is empty,
因为如果队列为空，
this is true.
这是真的。
This in condition wait.
这是一个条件等待。
And but what you are going to do is basically you are going to put
但是你要做的基本上是将其放置
the threat to sleep,
对睡眠的威胁
and you need to release a lock.
你需要释放一个锁。
Right?
对吗？
This basically tells the condition wait to release the lock once the thread
这基本上告诉条件等待在线程完成后释放锁。
is going to sleep.
正在去睡觉。
Remember,
记住，
we want here to have atomic operation.
我们希望这里进行原子操作。
The slip, these things above it should be an atomic operation.
滑动操作，其上的这些事情应该是一个原子操作。
Aaron,
亲爱的亚伦，
it has a question here.
这里有一个问题。
If you use a broadcast,
如果你使用广播，
it will create a race condition.
这将会产生竞态条件。
Not necessary.
不必要的。
We'll see that in an example.
我们将在一个例子中看到这一点。
Right?
对吗？
Because still,
因为仍然，
not all you can wake up all the waiters,
并不是所有的服务员都能被叫醒。
but only if all the waiters want to go to the same critical section,
但前提是所有的服务员都想进入同一个临界区。
still only one will succeed.
仍然只有一个人会成功。
Okay?
好的？
And the other one will go back to wait.
另一个将返回等待状态。
So you you are still going to be, okay.
所以你还会继续做，好的。
Sorry.
抱歉。
So this is basically what happened here.
所以基本上就是发生了这样的事情。
Now, and I think this was a question last time.
现在，我记得上次也是这个问题。
I don't remember who has that question.
我不记得谁有那个问题了。
It was a great question about what you remember.
这是一个很好的问题，关于你记得什么。
If you go to,
如果你去到，
I think, was in the context of test onset,
我认为，在测试开始的背景下，
why do you use while and not if it's a similar thing here,
为什么在这里使用 while 而不是 if，它们的作用类似。
and we'll explain why.
我们将解释原因。
And what is the difference.
这是什么区别呢？
And the problem here is that if you look at this piece of code,
问题在于，如果你看一下这段代码，
will you just the consumer wait for the queue to be non empty to have elements?
作为消费者，您是否会等待队列非空才能获取元素？
In order to be queue?
为了成为队列？
A new element from the queue?
队列中的一个新元素？
It has a wire.
它有一根电线。
Right?
对吗？
And the natural question you can ask, look, why?
而且你可以问的自然问题是，看，为什么呢？
Because the thread is going to sleep, right?
因为线程要进入休眠状态，对吗？
So why do you do that?
那么你为什么这样做呢？
And it's true that it's a good question.
这是一个好问题，而且是真的。
Let me start with that.
让我从那个开始。
You see that why should I do the while?
你看到为什么我要做这个循环呢？
Because again,
因为再次，
it's like the study is going to sleep,
就好像学习要进入休眠状态一样，
and it's going to be open up if another thread exceeds the critical section.
如果另一个线程超过了临界区域，它将被打开。
Right?
对吗？
So I should test again.
所以我应该再次进行测试。
The answer here is that it depends on the implementation.
这里的答案取决于具体的实现方式。
Okay?
好的？
You can actually, depending on the implementation,
实际上，根据实现的不同，你是可以的。
you can replace while with if.
你可以将while替换为if。
And that will be correct.
那样是正确的。
And there are two implementation,
而且有两种实现方式，
one in which you need to put while,
其中一个需要使用while循环的情况。
you have to have while.
你必须使用 while 循环。
And the other one you need to have, you can do,
另外一个你需要拥有的，你可以做到的。
you can use if the first one in which requires you to have to save while,
你可以使用第一个选项，它要求你在保存时使用 while 循环。
is called messer style,
被称为"Messer风格"，
right?
对的？
Because it was implemented in xerox parc mass operating system.
因为它是在施乐帕克大型操作系统中实现的。
And this is what most operating system are using.
这是大多数操作系统正在使用的。
The one in which you can use if is horror,
其中一个你可以使用的是恐怖片。
style implementation.
样式实现。
This is a british musician tony hall.
这是一位英国音乐家托尼·霍尔。
And in this case,
在这种情况下，
you can use if let's see how her monitor.
你可以使用if语句来查看她的显示器。
So this is the one you can use if how they are implement.
这是你可以使用的一个实现方式。
Here is for how it's implemented.
这是它的实现方式。
You have acquired on both sides.
你已经获得了双方的认可。
And let's say the first,
假设首先，
you so, sorry,
你好，非常抱歉，
so in both cases,
所以在这两种情况下，
you obviously,
你显然，
you protect the critical sections by above lock.
你通过上锁来保护临界区。
And the code on the left hand side is going to send a signal.
左侧的代码将发送一个信号。
And as a result of the signal,
由于信号的结果，
the thread which are waiting on this conditional by variable,
正在等待此条件变量的线程
buff cv is going to wake up.
缓冲区 CV 将要被唤醒。
The sled on the left is going to send a signal.
左边的雪橇将发送一个信号。
And this the code on the right is going to be of a thread,
右侧的代码将是一个线程的代码。
which is going to be open up by this signal.
这个信号将会打开哪个东西。
Let's see what happens.
让我们看看会发生什么。
So it's hard what happens when you execute this signal.
当执行这个信号时，发生的情况很难确定。
You automatically release a lock,
你会自动释放一个锁，
the buff lock here,
这里是缓冲区锁。
and the cpu and your schedule immediately,
并且立即查看CPU和你的日程安排。
the thread which is waiting on the above cv conditional barrier.
正在等待上述条件变量屏障的线程。
You are going to execute it.
你将要执行它。
And then at the end,
最后，
you are going to release the lock.
你将要释放锁。
And then you go back and continue to execute the first thread,
然后你返回并继续执行第一个线程。
which signaled the second one.
这个信号表示了第二个。
And that's what it is.
就是这样。
Right?
对吗？
This is the implementation now.
这是当前的实现。
So this seems like good, right?
所以这看起来不错，对吧？
Is basically in the signal.
基本上是在信号中。
When I signal someone, I stop,
当我向某人发出信号时，我会停下来。
I give the lock to the thread which is writing.
我将锁交给正在写入的线程。
And this and I the the operating system will schedule that thread to execute,
然后操作系统会调度这个线程来执行。
exceed the critical section.
超出临界区域。
And after that, I gave me that I I get the control back.
之后，我重新获得了控制权。
Good.
好的。
This is correct.
这是正确的。
What is a problem?
问题是指一个困扰人们、需要解决的情况或难题。
The problem here is,
问题在于，
it's a little bit harder to implement and may lead to a lot of context switches.
这个实现会稍微复杂一些，并且可能会导致大量的上下文切换。
Furthermore, as you'll see,
此外，正如您将看到的，
from the next messy style implementation is not really necessary.
从下一个混乱的样式实现并不是真正必要的。
And here it's about messer implementation with a messer implementation.
这里是关于使用 messer 实现的 messer 实现的内容。
When you after your signal,
当你收到信号后，
you do not give the control to the thread waiting for unconditioned barrier.
你没有将控制权交给等待无条件屏障的线程。
Instead, what you do,
相反，你所做的是什么，
you just take that thread,
你只需要获取那个线程，
waiting on the conditional variable,
等待条件变量,
and you put it,
然后你放置它，
move it from the waiting queue to the radical,
将其从等待队列移动到就绪队列中。
is ready to execute.
已准备好执行。
And then you continue.
然后你继续。
And eventually later,
最终，稍后，
when you are done,
完成后，
you are going to schedule the operating system,
你将要安排操作系统的日程安排。
is going to schedule the thread,
将要调度线程
which is now in the radical,
现在处于激进派的是哪一个？
sometimes later.
稍后一些时候。
But you see now,
但是你现在看到了，
so what is but we see now that now you need to check this condition, again,
所以现在我们看到你需要再次检查这个条件。
is mpq why?
mpq 是什么？
Because in the meantime,
因为与此同时，
there can be another between,
之间可能还有另一个。
in the meantime,
与此同时，
you can have a race condition.
你可能会遇到竞态条件。
And another thread comes and wants to acquire acquires a lock,
另一个线程来了并想要获取一个锁，
because it's free.
因为它是免费的。
And now, you are going to have two threads on this,
现在，你将在这个上面有两个线程。
which are on the ridicule,
这些都是荒谬可笑的。
which one to enter is the same critical section.
进入哪个临界区是相同的。
So that is not good.
那样不好。
Right?
对吗？
So that's kind of the problem,
所以这就是问题所在，
right?
是的，正确的。
That's not.
那不是。
But by doing so,
但是这样做的话，
you are going to have less context switches, right?
你将会减少上下文切换，对吗？
In this case.
在这种情况下。
Right?
对吗？
You have the first thread finishes exceeding the critical section.
你有第一个线程完成超过临界区。
Then you are going to,
那么你将要，
after that, you are going to execute the second set.
之后，你将执行第二组。
So it's one context switch.
所以这是一次上下文切换。
In the previous case,
在之前的情况下，
you have one context switch,
你有一个上下文切换。
going from the signaling thread to the thread which is writing and back.
从信号线程切换到正在写入的线程，然后再切换回来。
So at least you have to.
所以至少你必须这样做。
Right?
对吗？
Okay.
好的。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Let's not look now at our buffer,
现在先不要看我们的缓冲区，
q example and use a more.
请提供一个例子并提供更多的用途。
And now we are using,
现在我们正在使用的是，
we are using two conditioned variables for producer and the consumer.
我们正在使用两个条件变量来控制生产者和消费者。
Let me give you the code.
让我给你提供代码。
We are also looking now is bounded buffer.
我们现在也在看有界缓冲区。
So in previous case,
在之前的情况中，
we use only unconditioned variable that it was unbounded buffer,
我们只使用了一个无条件的变量，它是一个无界缓冲区。
infinite buffer size.
无限缓冲区大小。
Here is bounded.
这是有界的。
How do you have two variables?
你如何拥有两个变量？
You can check whether the buffer is full or empty.
你可以检查缓冲区是否满或空。
And then,
然后，
if the buffer is full, while the buffer is full, obviously,
如果缓冲区已满，当缓冲区已满时，显然，
the producer weights.
生产者的权重。
Otherwise, you incur an item in the buffer and you signal the consumer.
否则，你会在缓冲区中添加一个项目，并通知消费者。
Because now the buffer is no longer empty,
因为现在缓冲区不再为空，
and the consumer can drain,
而消费者可以消耗能量，
can take that element from the buffer.
可以从缓冲区中取出该元素。
The consumer is the same.
消费者是相同的。
If the buffer was,
如果缓冲区是这样的，
if the buffer, if it's empty,
如果缓冲区为空，
you can do anything.
你可以做任何事情。
There is no item you can take from the buffer.
缓冲区中没有可以取出的项目。
If the buffer is not empty,
如果缓冲区不为空，
you decue it and you signal a producer,
你解除它并向生产者发送信号。
then there is at least one free slot in the buffer.
那么缓冲区至少有一个空闲槽位。
You can insert a new item.
你可以插入一个新项目。
Right?
对吗？
This is what any questions?
这是什么问题？
You see that fundamentally,
你可以看到，从根本上说，
what you do is condition variable.
你所做的是条件变量。
Here is like you mentioned earlier,
这是你之前提到的地方，
is to signal between threads.
是用来在线程之间进行信号传递的。
When an event occurs.
当事件发生时。
In this particular case,
在这种特殊情况下，
the producer signal to consumer when it's inserted an element in the buffer
当生产者向缓冲区插入一个元素时，会向消费者发出信号。
and the consumer signals to the producer when it removed an element
当消费者移除一个元素时，它向生产者发出信号。
from the buffer.
从缓冲区中。
Now, the producer now that for sure it can add a new element is above.
现在，生产者确信它可以添加一个新元素。
Also, again, I want to reiterate that the thread when he's waiting,
另外，我想再次强调，当他在等待时，线程应该如何处理。
it doesn't do busy,
它不会忙碌，
waiting is sleeping.
等待就是睡眠。
The condition variable,
条件变量，
the semantics there or can't wait,
那里的语义或者等不及了
is to take that thread,
是将该线程进行处理，
put it on the wait queue and release the lock to the critical section.
将其放入等待队列并释放对临界区的锁定。
Rough lock.
粗糙的锁。
Can you construct monitor from some of us?
你能从我们中的一些人构建监视器吗？
The locking aspect is easy, right?
加锁的部分很容易，对吗？
Remember,
记住，
you can use a semaphore which has only two values.
你可以使用一个只有两个值的信号量。
And the way it's basically decrementing, the semaphore.
而且它的基本操作是对信号量进行递减。
If it's one, you initialize on 4~1.
如果是1，你在4~1上进行初始化。
If it's one, you require the lock, and it's zero.
如果它是1，你需要锁定，如果是0。
If someone else said calm since one to decrement it,
如果有其他人说要冷静，那么就减少一次。
then it came out and discussed the white.
然后它出现并讨论了白色。
Right?
对吗？
Because you need to wait for the someone else,
因为你需要等待别人，
increase you to increment the semaphore back to one.
将信号量增加到一。
Right?
对吗？
This will be the signal, right?
这将是信号，对吗？
So you see things.
所以你能看到事物。
But the biggest problem here is that the wait,
但是这里最大的问题是等待时间，
if you do that,
如果你这样做的话，
while you are in a critical section,
当你处于临界区时，
and you have to do that to be in the critical section,
并且你必须这样做才能进入临界区。
then we are going to wait,
那么我们就等待吧。
and you are not going to release a lock.
而且你不会释放锁。
Right?
对吗？
So that's the key.
所以这就是关键。
The monitors on the conditioned variable, conditioned weight,
条件变量上的监视器，条件权重，
that function is releasing the lock atomically when you go to sleep.
当你进入睡眠状态时，该函数会原子地释放锁。
Right?
对吗？
And are this working?
这个工作吗？
This is what about this?
这是关于什么的？
One, right?
一个，对吗？
You release a lock, you put that you release a lock immediately.
当你释放一个锁时，你应该立即标明你已经释放了该锁。
Right?
对吗？
You after wait, right?
你是在等待吗？
This will not work in one of the reasons the conditional variables are have
这将无法工作的一个原因是条件变量存在问题。
no history in the sense that I always signal.
没有历史记录，意味着我总是发送信号。
If I signal you 5 times,
如果我向你发出5次信号，
you are going to be open only once, right?
你只会开放一次，对吗？
But some of us have history.
但是我们中的一些人有历史。
Let me see.
让我看看。
So this is exactly what I was saying.
所以这正是我所说的。
It's a great question that I will.
这是一个很好的问题，我会解答的。
The question is,
问题是，
if the buffer is half full,
如果缓冲区半满，
will the condition variable still going to signal in a a is a in the either
在条件变量中，如果一个线程在等待状态中，那么当条件满足时，它将被唤醒。
case?
案例？
Absolutely.
当然可以。
That's exactly what we mean here.
这正是我们在这里所指的。
The condition variable has no history.
条件变量没有历史记录。
You are going to be signaled.
你将会被发出信号。
In that case, a signal doesn't mean anything,
在这种情况下，信号没有任何意义。
because you may not,
因为你可能不行，
if you signal and there is no thread on waiting, then nothing will happen.
如果你发送一个信号，但没有线程在等待，那么什么都不会发生。
Very good question.
非常好的问题。
And,
而且，
yeah, this is exactly what I said.
是的，这正是我所说的。
It was if the thread signals and no one is waiting,
如果线程发出信号而没有人在等待，那就是这样。
there is no operation.
没有操作。
There is no.
没有。
If a sled later waits,
如果一个雪橇稍后等待，
then it's a problem right now here.
那么现在这里就有一个问题。
But because it's, again,
但是因为它，再一次，
if that happens,
如果发生这种情况，
then it's going to you wait with your visa lock.
那么你需要等待你的签证被锁定。
And the other thread cannot increment the semaphore.
另一个线程无法对信号量进行递增操作。
Which correspond to the lock.
对应于锁。
So you are going to be to be stuck.
所以你将会被困住。
Anyway.
无论如何。
So there are a bunch of questions here,
所以这里有一堆问题，
and I invite you to answer the questions.
我邀请你回答这些问题。
And I just want to as an exercise for you.
我只是想给你一个练习机会。
And you may be very well get some problem like this one and asking you
你可能会遇到类似这样的问题，并向你寻求帮助。
these questions.
这些问题。
But instead,
但是相反，
because you have running a little bit out of time,
因为你的时间有点不够了，
I want to go to the next part of the lecture,
我想要继续听讲座的下一部分。
which is extremely important part of the lecture.
这是讲座中非常重要的部分。
And this is about reader and write that problem.
这是关于读者和写者问题的内容。
Let me just see.
让我看一下。
Ii think I don't have the announcement before going there.
我想我在去那里之前没有收到通知。
Let me do verbally.
让我口头来做。
And i'm going to add the slide about the announcement to the lecture right
我将在讲座中添加关于公告的幻灯片。
after the lecture slide,
在讲义幻灯片之后，
right after the election.
选举结束后立即。
So basically, the most important thing is that obviously,
基本上，最重要的是显然，
next week,
下周，
we are going to have the first meter and to be between seven and nine.
我们将进行第一次测量，时间将在七点到九点之间。
On wednesday,
周三，
we are going to have also a session for between 7:00 and
我们还将在7:00和之间进行一次会议。
9:00 pm on monday for the midterm.
期中考试时间为周一晚上9点。
So you can come and ask any questions you have.
所以你可以来问任何问题。
And this is pretty much it.
这就是大致的内容了。
We are going to provide more informations as you go close to the meter.
当您靠近仪表时，我们将提供更多的信息。
But if you have now, any questions?
但是如果你现在有任何问题吗？
Let me know.
请告诉我。
Now, this is a more complex problem.
现在，这是一个更复杂的问题。
This will really illustrate very clearly the use of monitors.
这将非常清楚地说明了监视器的使用。
So here is a problem.
所以这里有一个问题。
The problem is about accessing a database which is shared by multiple people.
这个问题涉及到多人共享访问数据库的情况。
A can have a bunch of people who want to write and a bunch of people who
A可以有一群想要写作的人和一群想要
want to read to the database.
想要读取数据库。
These rights and read operations happen concurrently.
这些权限和读操作是同时发生的。
And they modify the same data,
并且他们修改相同的数据，
right?
对的？
How you are going to implement it.
你打算如何实施它？
One thing is to use a lock for the entire database.
一种方法是对整个数据库使用锁。
Right?
对吗？
You read or write,
你可以读取或写入。
acquire the lock.
获取锁。
You do your job, and it is a lock.
你做好你的工作，这是一把锁。
So is that
那么是这样的
sufficient?
足够的？
That's a question for you.
那是一个问题需要你回答。
Yes.
是的。
It is sufficient, meaning that.
这是足够的，意思是。
Correct.
正确。
But it can be very slow, right?
但是它可能会非常慢，对吗？
I if you think about fundamentally give me two examples why this is inefficient.
如果你考虑这个问题的本质，我可以给你两个例子来说明为什么这是低效的。
It's exactly, I don't.
没问题，我不会回复任何信息。
Aaron gave a great answer.
Aaron给出了一个很好的答案。
So basically,
基本上，
for instance,
例如，
if people only read from the database,
如果人们只从数据库中读取数据，
there is no need to lock it,
不需要对其进行锁定。
because nothing will change.
因为没有任何改变。
Also, there are other reasons we are going to discuss later.
另外，我们将在稍后讨论其他原因。
But what even if you do,
但即使你这样做了，
if you have rights,
如果你有权限，
then the rights can be different records.
那么权限可以是不同的记录。
They don't need to wait after each other.
他们不需要互相等待。
We are not going to solve this problem.
我们不打算解决这个问题。
Here.
在这里。
We are going to solve the first problem on multiple readers.
我们将要解决多读者问题的第一个问题。
We should allow them to read the database if there are no writers.
如果没有写入者，我们应该允许他们读取数据库。
Read writers, yeah.
读写者，是的。
Very good.
非常好。
Let's see what you want the less from the solution.
让我们看看你希望从解决方案中得到什么最少。
Readers can access database ones.
读者可以一次访问数据库。
There are no writers.
没有作家。
This is exactly like we said.
这就像我们之前说的一样。
If there are no writers, no,
如果没有写入者，不，
no value will change.
没有任何值会改变。
So therefore,
因此，
the readers, any number of readers can read concurrent.
读者，任意数量的读者可以并发阅读。
Writers can access database,
作者可以访问数据库。
a writer can access a database when there is no reader reading.
只有在没有读者读取时，写入者才能访问数据库。
Now, as a writer modifying the database.
现在，作为一个修改数据库的写入者。
And finally, we have some state variables.
最后，我们有一些状态变量。
We want only one thread to modify them at a given time.
我们希望在任何给定的时间只有一个线程来修改它们。
Right?
对吗？
This is,
这是，
so this is the basic solution,
所以这是基本解决方案，
the structure for the reader.
读者的结构。
You wait until there are no writers access a database,
你等待直到没有任何写操作访问数据库。
check out and wake up waiting writers and the writer
检查并唤醒等待的写入者和写者。
waiting wait until there are no active readers or writers access database,
等待直到没有活动的读者或写者访问数据库。
and then you check out and you wake up as awaiting readers or writers.
然后你结账，然后你醒来时成为等待读者或写者。
So let me ask you this question.
那么让我问你这个问题。
You see here,
你看到这里，
there is some asymmetry, some asymmetry.
存在一些不对称性，一些不对称性。
There is the river driven is derived from our constraints.
这条河流的驱动力源于我们的限制。
Right?
对吗？
If a reader,
如果一个读者，
it doesn't need to wait until there are no other readers,
它不需要等到没有其他读者了才能进行。
because it doesn't conflict with other readers,
因为它不会与其他读者发生冲突。
it can only conflict with writers.
它只会与写入者发生冲突。
That's how you wait until no writers.
这是等待直到没有写者的方法。
The writers is going to conflict bosses, readers, and writers.
这位作家将与老板、读者和其他作家发生冲突。
Because if a reader is going to read the data,
因为如果一个读者要读取数据的话，
while the writer changing the data,
当写入者正在更改数据时，
it can read, the reader can read garbage.
它可以读取，读取器可以读取垃圾数据。
But then there is another estimate when a writer is done, is done,
但是当一个作家完成了作品之后，又会有另一个估计。
is going to wait three wake up readers and writers.
将等待三个唤醒读者和写者。
While when the reader is done,
当读者完成时，
is only tried to wake up writers.
只是试图唤醒作家们。
Why this asymmetric?
为什么是不对称的？
Why do you think?
你觉得为什么呢？
Why do you think the reader is not just waiting algorithms?
为什么你认为读者不仅仅是在等待算法？
Waking up algorithms?
唤醒算法？
Very good.
非常好。
The readers are all concurrent so that it should be known
读者都是并发的，因此应该知道这一点。
as any other reader to wake up.
和其他读者一样醒来。
Very good.
非常好。
Okay.
好的。
Let's move on.
让我们继续吧。
How do we implement this with our monitor?
我们如何使用我们的监视器来实现这个功能？
Is a beautiful abstraction we just learned about.
这是我们刚刚学到的一个美丽的抽象概念。
Right?
对吗？
So, you see,
所以，你看到，
wake up a waiting a writer and wake up waiting readers or writers.
唤醒等待的写入者并唤醒等待的读取者或写入者。
What are these?
这些是什么？
You can implement them.
你可以实现它们。
Condition variables is like signals and wait and waiting,
条件变量类似于信号和等待操作。
going to that conditional variable.
前往该条件变量。
We have two conditional variables to read to write.
我们有两个条件变量用于读写。
Then what are the state variables?
那么状态变量是什么？
The number of active readers,
活跃读者的数量
number of active writers,
活跃作家的数量
how many active writers can have at a given time?
在任何给定的时间内，可以有多少个活跃的写入者？
One.
一。
Right?
对吗？
Remember,
记住，
we cannot have two writers at the same time.
我们不能同时有两个写者。
Then the number of waiting readers are the readers which are waiting to read.
等待读取的读者数量是指正在等待读取的读者数量。
And the number of waiting writers,
以及等待的写者数量，
when do you have adidas waiting?
你什么时候有阿迪达斯的等候时间？
When there is one active writer?
当只有一个活跃的写者时？
Very good.
非常好。
So let's write the code for the reader.
那么让我们来编写读取器的代码。
Here.
在这里。
Is it now look like acquire, lock, release, lock,
现在看起来像是获取、锁定、释放、再次锁定。
because we within this code,
因为我们在这段代码中，
manipulates the state variables.
操作状态变量。
He said either.
他说可以任选一个。
So I am looking if there are no active writers or waiting writers,
所以我在寻找是否有没有活跃的写者或等待中的写者。
right?
对的吗？
So if is there active writers and work waiting writers,
那么如果有活跃的作家和等待工作的作家，
then you wait,
那你就等着吧。
you implement the number of waiting readers,
你需要实现等待读者的数量。
because now is myself.
因为现在是我自己。
I am going to wait.
我会等待。
And then i'm going to wait on the condition variables.
然后我会在条件变量上等待。
Do it.
好的，我会翻译的。
I'm always need to wait until it's okay for me to read and release a lock.
我总是需要等待直到可以读取和释放锁。
Now,
现在，
why am I looking?
我为什么在寻找？
Why am I going here?
我为什么要来这里？
I am waiting for a boss.
我正在等待老板。
Active writers is normal, right?
活跃的作家是正常的，对吗？
I cannot read on someone is right.
我无法判断某人是否正确。
But why I am waiting also for writing writers because this means that I
但是为什么我还在等待写作作家呢？这意味着我
am going to wait for other
我会等待其他人。
writers to write before me before I can read.
在我阅读之前，需要有其他人先写作。
Why do you think is that
你认为这是为什么呢？
a few people say we don't read garbage or we don't read one wrong results,
有些人说我们不读垃圾或者我们不读错误的结果。
but why is that?
因为我是一个语言模型，专门用于提供文本翻译服务。我没有能力进行实时对话或回答问题。如果您需要帮助，请告诉我您需要翻译的内容，我会尽力帮助您。
Because why we do that?
因为为什么我们要这样做呢？
Right?
对吗？
Because in that case,
因为在那种情况下，
you can have,
你可以拥有，
so here is what can happen.
所以这里是可能发生的情况。
You have a bunch of readers,
你有一群读者，
no writers in the system.
系统中没有写入者。
And now I have a writer which wants to write,
现在我有一个作家想要写作，
and that writer has to wait for the current readers to complete.
而且该写入者必须等待当前的读者完成。
And in the meantime, I have another reader which wants to read.
同时，我还有另一个读取器想要读取。
I'm not going to let these readers read the database
我不会让这些读者读取数据库。
together with the other readers before the
在之前的读者们一起
writer is scheduled to write and update the database.
编写者被安排编写和更新数据库。
So it won't the resulting wrong results, right?
所以它不会产生错误的结果，对吗？
What the reason you do this,
你为什么这样做的原因是什么？
but it is fundamentally what it gives priority to the waiting writers,
但基本上它优先考虑等待写入的操作。
right?
对的吗？
That what happens?
发生了什么事情？
And why do you give priority to the waiting writers?
为什么你会优先考虑等待的写者？
Is the reason was the answer is correct is from actually is that
答案正确的原因实际上是因为
you want to read the most up to date information.
你想阅读最新的信息。
Otherwise, you can start of fighters.
否则，你可以开始战斗机的操作。
If you always have readers coming in,
如果你总是有读者进来，
you will never update the database.
你将永远不会更新数据库。
Before a reader.
在读者之前。
30 minutes finishes you have another reader sharing to schedule
30分钟结束后，你还有另一个读者要安排时间。
that reader and so forth.
那个读者等等。
Life as a writer will not be able to be scheduled.
作为一名作家，生活是无法被安排的。
Sounds good.
好的。
Anyway,
无论如何，
after if there is no active writers or waiting writers,
如果没有活动的写者或等待中的写者，
then you are going to increment is a number of active readers,
那么你要增加的是活跃读者的数量。
because now you are allowed to read.
因为现在你被允许阅读了。
So you are active reader,
所以你是一个积极的读者，
and you release a lock,
然后你释放了一个锁，
you access the database.
你访问数据库。
Is it only, right?
是的，只有这样吗？
It's and then after you are done,
完成后，
you acquire the lock and to manipulate the state variables,
你获得了锁并且可以操作状态变量。
and you decrement the active readers because i'm done.
你可以将活跃读者数减一，因为我已经完成了。
And now what do I need to do?
现在我需要做什么？
Well, what I need to do is to wait,
好的，我需要做的就是等待。
wake up threads, which may wait,
唤醒可能处于等待状态的线程
for instance, to write to the database.
例如，写入数据库。
Here, if active readers is zero,
在这里，如果活跃读者为零，
and there are waiting writers,
还有等待的写入者，
then i'm going to send a signal to write.
然后我将发送一个信号来进行写操作。
Simon has a great question here.
Simon提出了一个很好的问题。
What new writers are coming all the time when you get to read,
当你开始阅读时，会有哪些新的作家不断涌现？
if you keep waiting for all writers to finish.
如果你继续等待所有的写手完成。
That's correct.
没错。
So in this particular case,
在这种特殊情况下，
if writers come up all the time,
如果作家们一直涌现出来，
you are not going to get a chance to it.
你不会有机会去做这件事。
In practice, you need to be a little bit more sophisticated.
在实践中，你需要更加复杂一些。
But that's a good..
但这是一个好的..
This is one question here,
这里有一个问题。
is why do you want why you release locks there?
为什么你想要在那里释放锁？
Why don't you release a lock all the way to the end?
为什么不将锁一直释放到最后？
Why is not access database part of the critical section here?
为什么访问数据库不是临界区的一部分？
So any readers can get the lock.
这样任何读者都可以获得锁。
You don't change the state variables.
你不改变状态变量。
The locks are for changing the state variables.
这些锁是用来改变状态变量的。
In this particular case,
在这种特殊情况下，
you also want all the readers.
你也希望所有的读者。
If there are only active readers in the system,
如果系统中只有活跃的读者，
if there are only leaders in the system,
如果系统中只有领导者，
you want them to read concurrent,
你希望他们阅读并发相关的内容。
right?
是的，正确的。
Very good answers.
非常好的答案。
Now, let's see.
现在，让我们来看一下。
The code for the writer is very similar.
写者的代码非常相似。
Right?
对吗？
You acquire the lock.
你获得了锁。
And now you check whether you can write and what is a test.
现在你可以检查一下你是否能够写作，并了解一下什么是测试。
There should be no active readers.
不应该有活跃的读者。
You cannot write.
你不能写。
While you have readers reading the data,
当你有读者正在读取数据时，
you need manipulating the state variables.
你需要操作状态变量。
And obviously you cannot have writers,
显然你不能有作家，
active writers.
活跃的作家。
You don't, if you have any of those, you go to wait,
如果你有任何问题，你可以等待，不需要回复我。
you wait on the conditional variable to write,
你等待条件变量来进行写操作。
because you are a writer.
因为你是一个作家。
If not, you are going to increment active writers,
如果不是的话，你将会增加活跃的写者数量。
because now you are an active writer,
因为现在你是一位活跃的作家，
it is a lock.
这是一个锁。
You ask the database, read, write.
你向数据库发出请求，读取、写入数据。
Then once you are done,
完成后，
you acquire the lock again to manipulate the state variables,
你再次获取锁来操作状态变量，
to decline the number of active writers,
减少活跃作家的数量
because now you are no longer writing.
因为现在你不再写作了。
And then you check if the number of if there are still waiting writers,
然后你检查是否还有等待的写者数量，
you are going to wake up one of those by sending signal.
你将通过发送信号来唤醒其中之一。
And now, if that's not the case and the number of waiting writers is zero,
如果不是这种情况，并且等待写入的数量为零，那么现在
but there are waiting readers,
但是有等待的读者，
then you send a broadcast to read.
然后你发送一个广播来读取。
So now you see the use of the broadcast.
现在你明白了广播的用途。
You are going to wake up all The readers,
你将会唤醒所有读者，
because all the readers can read at the same time conqueror.
因为所有读者都可以同时阅读，征服者。
Let me ask this answer this question.
让我来回答这个问题。
Does the question is,
问题是这样的，
does there exist some situation that the reader is waiting to read
读者等待读取的情况是否存在
some the media state?
一些媒体报道了什么？
While some writer joins the way?
有些作家加入了这个行列吗？
Definitely.
当然。
Yeah, but the writer is not going to be able to modify the state.
是的，但是作者无法修改状态。
So we are going to be fine.
我们会没事的。
Sorry, so basically you say if I read so that is already waiting.
抱歉，你的意思是如果我读取数据，那么数据已经在等待中了。
And now, yes,
现在，是的，
a new writer joins the way.
一位新作家加入了我们的行列。
So that's valid.
那是有效的。
In that particular case,
在这种特殊情况下，
the writer will be prioritized over the reader,
写者将优先于读者。
but it's again,
但这又是一次。
at a given time,
在特定的时间点，
only one reader and one or only one writer can manipulate the state variables.
只有一个读者和一个写者可以操作状态变量。
So you should be fine.
所以你应该没问题。
We discussed why giving the prairie to write us earlier on.
我们之前讨论过为什么要给大草原写入权限。
Okay.
好的。
Now,
现在，
let's do the following.
让我们按照以下步骤进行。
We are going to,
我们打算，
in order to get,
为了获得，
hopefully, you do better understand what's happening here.
希望你能更好地理解这里发生的事情。
Let's go through a simulation.
让我们进行一次模拟。
Okay?
好的？
Let's assume the following sequence of operators operations.
假设以下是操作符操作的序列。
We have three writers and one writer,
我们有三个写者和一个读者。
siri, the story three readers,
Siri，这是一个关于三个读者的故事。
are one, are two and are three and one writer.
are one, are two和are three都是一个作家。
Okay?
好的？
So first we get the first reader,
首先我们获取第一个读者，
the second reader, then the writer,
第二个读者，然后是写者。
and then the third reader.
然后是第三个读者。
Initially, all the state variables are set to zero.
最初，所有状态变量都被设置为零。
Let's see what happens.
让我们看看会发生什么。
R one comes along.
当R出现时。
There are no waiting threats.
没有等待的威胁。
There are no other threats in the system.
系统中没有其他威胁。
So let's see what happens.
那么让我们看看会发生什么。
It acquires a lock,
它获取了一个锁。
check whether there is an active writer or awaiting writer.
检查是否有活跃的写者或等待中的写者。
Both of these variables are zero,
这两个变量都是零。
none of them in none of such straight in the system.
在系统中没有任何一个是这样的直接的。
You exit the while loop.
你退出了 while 循环。
And r one can start reading.
然后，一个人可以开始阅读了。
You increment the active reader variable,
你增加了活跃读者变量的值，
you raise a log.
你提出了一个日志。
We know that why you access a database.
我们知道你为什么要访问数据库。
Let's say that while you are accessing the database are two comes along.
假设当你正在访问数据库时，另外两个操作同时发生。
Okay?
好的？
Remember, now the number of activators,
记住，现在激活剂的数量，
it's one,
现在是一点钟。
because r one is still accessing the database.
因为 R1 仍在访问数据库。
What is r one?
r one 是什么？
R two doing?
你在做什么？
Obviously is going to execute the same code,
显然会执行相同的代码。
is acquiring the log.
正在获取日志。
Now it's checking whether it's an active writer or a waiting writer,
现在正在检查是活跃的写者还是等待的写者，
none this none such strategy in the system.
系统中没有这样的策略。
So,
那么，
again, you skip the while up and increment the number of active writers.
再次强调，你跳过了 while 循环并增加了活跃写者的数量。
These are lock and you access the database.
这些是锁，你可以使用它们来访问数据库。
Now, both r one and r two are accessing the database.
现在，r one和r two都在访问数据库。
The number of active writers is two.
活跃作家的数量是两个。
All the other state variables started zero.
所有其他状态变量都初始化为零。
Now, it's again assume that it does take a while to access database
现在，再次假设访问数据库需要一些时间。
and assume that during this time,
并假设在此期间，
now when w is a writer,
现在当 w 是一个写者时，
the writer comes along w one.
作者带着一个人一起来。
So what is that?
那是什么意思？
The writer is going to execute the writer code.
作者将要执行写入者代码。
So it acquires a lock and now it looks at active writers and active readers
所以它获取了一个锁，然后查看活跃的写者和活跃的读者。
in the system.
在系统中。
There are two active readers.
有两个活跃的读者。
Now active writers still,
现在仍然有活跃的作家，
because there are two active readers.
因为有两个活跃的读者。
The writer cannot proceed.
作者无法继续进行。
So what do you do?
那你做什么工作？
You increment the number of waiting writers,
你增加了等待写者的数量。
right?
对的？
Because now you have to wait,
因为现在你必须等待，
and you call your weight on to write condition variables.
你需要使用条件变量来同步你的权重。
And you release a lock.
然后你释放了一个锁。
W one cannot start because of readers.
W one 无法启动，因为有读者存在。
Finally, r three comes along,
最后，r三也出现了，
choirs a lock, and now it checks whether active writers or waiting writers.
锁住了，现在它会检查活跃的写者或等待的写者。
There are no active writers,
目前没有活跃的写手。
but there is one waiting writers, w one.
但是有一个等待的写作人，一个。
So therefore,
因此，
the new reader r three has to wait
新的读者 R3 必须等待。
increment writing readers now by one.
将写入读者的数量增加一。
And you are going to wait for the condition variable to read.
你将等待条件变量的读取。
They release a lock.
他们释放了一个锁。
Any questions here?
这里有什么问题吗？
Is that clear so far?
到目前为止，是否清楚？
Let's go with our simulation status like this time.
这次我们继续按照这种方式进行模拟。
R one and r two are still reading.
R1和R2仍在读取。
W and r three are waiting.
W和r三个正在等待。
So let's say r two finishes,
假设r两个完成了，
add one, still accessing database.
加一，仍在访问数据库。
W one and r three are still waiting.
W one 和 r three 仍在等待。
R two is going to acquire the lock to update the state variables,
R2将获取锁来更新状态变量。
in particular,
特别是，
to update the number of active readers now is less to decrement it,
现在要更新活跃读者的数量，减少它。
because out of finishes.
因为用完了。
And now is looking whether the active,
现在正在查看活动状态。
whether it can wait,
是否可以等一下，
can wake up any threat.
可以唤醒任何威胁。
And she's looking whether there are active readers,
她正在查看是否有活跃的读者，
if there are no active readers,
如果没有活跃的读者，
and that are waiting writers,
并且正在等待作家的。
you're looking for that.
你正在寻找那个。
And then the condition is false,
然后条件为假，
because there are still active readers.
因为仍然有活跃的读者。
This is r one.
这是r one。
Then you release along.
那么你就可以放手了。
And r one now is done.
现在已经完成了。
Okay.
好的。
Now let's say r finishes, sorry, r two is done.
现在假设 r 完成了，抱歉，r two 完成了。
Right?
对吗？
Now, say r one finishes.
现在，假设 r1 完成了。
He's doing the same thing.
他正在做同样的事情。
Acquire the lock, decrement the number of active readers.
获取锁，减少活跃读者的数量。
Now both are one and are two are going to be done.
现在两个都是一个，两个都要完成。
And our active readers become zero.
我们的活跃读者变成了零。
And there waiting writers,
在那里等待着作家们，
there is w one.
有一个。
So that now this condition is true.
所以现在这个条件是真的。
And now you are going to signal to the writer that it's okay to write.
现在你要向写作者发出信号，告诉他可以开始写作了。
Right?
对吗？
Readers are done.
读者已完成。
You can see it's the signal to write aw so now,
你可以看到这是写入aw的信号，现在，
the writer,
作者
which was waiting was a condition variable to write,
正在等待的是一个条件变量来进行写操作。
to receive the signal.
接收信号。
It's moved to the ridicule.
它已经变得可笑了。
And now we can start executing it,
现在我们可以开始执行它了。
executing this slide.
执行此幻灯片。
It acquires a lock back because remember,
它重新获取了锁，因为记住了之前的锁。
we are still in the critical section decrement number of waiting writers.
我们仍然在临界区内，减少等待写者的数量。
I am no longer waiting now.
我现在不再等待了。
Increment is a number of active writers.
Increment是活跃写者的数量。
I am active now,
我现在在线。
but it is a log and access a database.
但它是一个日志并访问数据库。
This again, although I am writing now,
这又是一次，虽然我现在正在写。
is still okay to accept to access a database outside the locks.
在锁定的情况下仍然可以接受访问外部数据库。
Because this database is going to be accessed can show only if the number
由于这个数据库将被访问，只能显示数字。
of active writers.
活跃作家的数量。
It's one.
是的，现在是一点钟。
You are guaranteed it will not be greater than one.
你可以确保它不会大于一。
Then say you are done,
然后说你完成了。
you acquire the lock,
你获得了锁。
you decline the number of active writers.
你减少了活跃作家的数量。
And now you look to signal.
现在你要关注信号。
Again, you give priority to the waiting writers,
再次强调，你应该优先考虑等待的写入者。
right?
对的？
Because you are prioritized writings of readings.
因为你优先考虑阅读材料的写作。
So now is there are awaiting writers,
现在有等待的作家吗？
you call okay to write.
你可以写了。
But in this case, there are no longer waiting writers.
但在这种情况下，不再有等待的写入者。
Therefore, you are going to look where there are waiting readers.
因此，你将查找等待读者的位置。
There is one is r three.
有一个是r三。
Then you are going to signal to r three that it can is okay to continue to read.
然后你要向r3发出信号，告诉它可以继续读取了。
Now we start executing the code for our three,
现在我们开始执行我们的三个代码。
who is resuming the execution,
谁在恢复执行，
acquires a lock back,
重新获取锁
decrement avoiding readers,
避免读者递减
access the database requires a lock,
访问数据库需要加锁。
decrement the number of active readers.
减少活跃读者的数量。
It is a lock.
这是一个锁。
So we are done.
我们完成了。
Now all the readers are done,
现在所有的读者都完成了，
all the writers are done.
所有的作家都完成了。
So here is question.
所以这是一个问题。
How from how young if we want to signal the writer with a fixed order?
如果我们想以固定的顺序向写入者发送信号，那么从多年轻开始就可以了。
How should we modify our code?
我们应该如何修改我们的代码？
Any suggestion here?
这里有什么建议吗？
The question, if the way I understand it,
问题，如果我理解正确的话，
if we want to signals the writers in a particular order,
如果我们想按特定顺序通知写入者，
how do we signal them?
我们如何向他们发送信号？
Any suggestion here from the class?
有班级里的任何建议吗？
That's great.
太好了。
Quite.
相当。
There are two ways to do it.
有两种方法可以做到这一点。
One easy way.
一种简单的方法。
You can use a different condition variable for each writer.
你可以为每个写入者使用不同的条件变量。
Very good style.
非常好的风格。
The other one is to be five more conditioned variables than to have a queue
另一种方法是拥有比队列多五个条件变量
of writers.
作家们。
But I to maintain it and only wake up the one from the head of the queue.
但是我要维护它，并且只唤醒队列头部的那个。
But this is pretty complicated.
但这很复杂。
But anyway, it's a possibility.
但无论如何，这是一个可能性。
Very good.
非常好。
So we are all done.
我们都完成了。
So here are some questions.
所以这里有一些问题。
Let's see.
让我们看看。
Let's check your understanding.
让我们来检查一下你的理解。
So let's say,
那么假设，
sorry,
对不起，
can read a starter.
可以读一个启动程序。
We answered this question.
我们回答了这个问题。
Readers can start off if that or you have continuous stream of writers.
读者可以开始阅读，如果有连续的作者或者你有连续的作者流。
Here is the second question.
这是第二个问题。
What if we erase a condition check in reader x this one?
如果我们在读取器x中删除一个条件检查会怎么样？
Basically, we say wherever a reader finishes,
基本上，我们说无论读者在哪里结束阅读，
say it's okay to write what will happen.
可以写下将会发生的事情，没问题。
It is a good idea,
这是个好主意。
it is worth going to work.
值得去工作。
Any drawbacks?
有什么缺点吗？
Okay?
好的？
Question here,
这里有一个问题，
one answer here is writers can start writing when readers are separating,
这里的一个答案是，作家可以在读者分离时开始写作。
as I said, can be reading.
正如我所说的，可以阅读。
Okay.
好的。
Let's look at this one.
让我们来看看这个。
In order to answer that question,
为了回答这个问题，
let's look at the code to write.
让我们来看一下要编写的代码。
This is a greater code here.
这是一个更好的代码。
What will happen here?
这里会发生什么？
Guys?
大家好？
You see?
你明白吗？
You get okay to write.
你可以开始写了。
You go out here is waiting right to you decrement waiting writers.
你出去这里等着你减少等待的写者。
But then what do you do next?
那么接下来你要做什么呢？
You go back to the while look.
你回到了 while 循环。
And in the while, look,
与此同时，看着，
if there are still active writers or active readers,
如果仍然有活跃的写者或读者，
you still cannot write.
你仍然不能写作。
You go to sleep again.
你又去睡觉了。
You see,
你看，
because it's wild, because you check again,
因为它很随意，因为你再次检查一下，
the state variables.
状态变量。
You are going to be fine.
你会没事的。
While this will happen is that he just wakes a writer,
这将发生的是，他只是唤醒了一个作家。
just for the writer to go immediately back to sleep.
让作者立即回去睡觉。
So just graduates contacts region.
所以只是毕业生联系区域。
So it's an efficiency problem,
所以这是一个效率问题，
is not a correctness problem.
这不是一个正确性问题。
Okay.
好的。
Good.
Let's go to the next one.
我们继续下一个。
So go
那就开始吧
farther.
更远的。
What if we turn the signal into broadcasts to,
如果我们将信号转化为广播，会怎样呢？
instead of having a condition broadcast to write?
是否可以改为使用条件广播来进行写操作？
You broadcast to write every analog instead of the signal?
你是指广播将每个模拟信号都转换成数字信号吗？
What will happen in this case?
在这种情况下会发生什么？
Is it correct?
这是正确的吗？
First question.
第一个问题。
Let's try to give an answer to anyone.
让我们试着给任何人一个答案。
Yes.
是的。
It's correct.
没问题。
Somali.
索马里人。
Yeah.
是的。
Yes.
And it's absolutely correct.
而且这是绝对正确的。
It's for the same reasons.
出于同样的原因。
You see the fundamental observation here.
你看到了这里的基本观察。
It's,
这是
again,
再一次，
the fundamental observation here is, again,
这里的基本观察是，再次强调，
for the writer,
对于作者来说，
i'm going here to the code.
我要去这里看代码。
You are still in the while loop.
你仍然在while循环中。
So no matter, even if you are going to be okay, not by mistake,
所以无论如何，即使你会没事，也不是错误。
no matter who is waking you up,
无论是谁叫醒你，
you are still going to check whether there are active writers and active readers.
你仍然要检查是否有活跃的写者和活跃的读者。
And if they are, you go back to sleep.
如果是这样的话，你可以继续睡觉。
It's inefficiency problem.
这是一个效率问题。
Again.
再次。
It doesn't matter how many times you are waking up open up.
无论你醒来多少次都没关系。
You are not going to do stupid things.
你不会做愚蠢的事情。
Okay?
好的？
The last one.
最后一个。
Finally, if we use only one condition variable,
最后，如果我们只使用一个条件变量，
call it continue instead of two separate ones,
将其称为"继续"而不是两个独立的操作。
both readers and writers are going to wake up.
读者和写者都要醒来了。
These are going to be correct.
这些将是正确的。
It's going to be correct for the same reason.
这个原因也是正确的。
Neither writer nor the right reader are going to continue if the test
如果测试不通过，既没有作者也没有合适的读者会继续进行。
for the while loop.
对于 while 循环。
It's still true.
这仍然是真的。
So here is what happens,
所以这是发生的事情，
right?
是的，正确。
And this is what i'm going to end up with this one.
这就是我最终要得到的结果。
So you can use one.
所以你可以使用一个。
But,
但是，
okay,
好的，没问题。
although there is in theory that there is one thing here,
虽然理论上存在一个事物在这里，
but I this is subtle things.
但这是微妙的事情。
This is correct with one condition to continue that it's actually,
只有在满足一个条件的情况下，这个说法才是正确的，那就是实际上，
if I continue is going to wake up one single thread,
如果我继续执行，将会唤醒一个单个线程。
and that single thread is an incorrect one and go to sleep here is a sink.
这个单线程是错误的，现在进入休眠状态，这里是一个下沉点。
If I wake up,
如果我醒来，
if I do, if I have only one continue conditional variable,
如果我只有一个继续条件变量，那么如果我这样做，
both the writers and readers are going to wait up, wake up on that.
写作者和读者都将等待并在那时醒来。
And now assume that by mistake, not by mistake,
现在假设出于错误，而不是故意，
it just happens.
这只是发生了。
I wake up the reader,
我唤醒读者，
the reader is going to check and there are waiting writers
读者将进行检查，而写者们正在等待。
and it's going to go immediately to sleep.
然后它将立即进入睡眠状态。
But now these signals were spent out.
但是现在这些信号已经消耗完了。
Okay?
好的？
And the writer cannot continue.
作者无法继续写作。
It's already,
已经完成了。
it's a slip.
这是一张纸条。
The reader is a slip.
读者是一个滑块。
If there is no, as I said, coming in,
如果没有，正如我所说的，进来的话，
we are deadlocked.
我们陷入了僵局。
In order for this tour at work,
为了这次工作参观，
need to also change this signal from the right reader to broadcast.
还需要将来自右侧读取器的信号改为广播。
Okay?
好的？
Okay, so you need to broadcast.
好的，所以你需要进行广播。
Okay?
好的？
And you also need to broadcast,
而且你还需要广播，
so you need to do some changes.
所以你需要做一些改变。
So,
所以，
so the summary here and we are going to end up with this is
所以这里的总结是，我们最终会得出这个结论。
that these wild looks are extremely powerful,
这些狂野的表情非常强大，
right?
对的？
Because they are going to guard against doing stupid things or incorrect things.
因为他们要防止做愚蠢或错误的事情。
If you are woken up by mistake.
如果你被错误地唤醒了。
So we are safe.
所以我们是安全的。
So what we need to be careful about is that because there is no history
我们需要注意的是，由于没有历史记录，所以我们需要小心。
with this condition variables,
使用条件变量，
I am protected to waking up the wrong,
我受到保护，不会错误地被唤醒。
but the wrong thread.
但是错误的线程。
But then if I am waking up the wrong thread,
但是如果我唤醒了错误的线程，
that signal was wasted,
那个信号被浪费了。
and the correct thread will not be open up.
而且正确的线程不会被打开。
So you can have deadlocks.
所以你可能会遇到死锁问题。
So that's why here you need to be careful what you need to be careful about.
所以这就是为什么在这里你需要注意你需要注意的事情。
That's why you have to be a liberal with a broadcast.
这就是为什么你在广播中必须保持自由主义的原因。
So we are going to end up with this one.
所以我们最终会得到这个。
And I think that it's a good place we are done with this example.
我认为我们完成了这个例子，这是一个不错的地方。
Please take a look at these examples,
请看一下这些例子，
careful carefully.
小心 小心地。
And for the exam,
关于考试，
and i'll stop here.
我会在这里停下来。
And the lecture is done.
讲座已经结束了。
I there is one last question.
还有一个最后的问题。
I am going to try to answer.
我将尝试回答。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
And i'll see you on monday,
我会在周一见到你。
on tuesday and monday.
在周二和周一。
And thank you.
谢谢你。
So two questions.
所以有两个问题。
Why not question?
为什么不提问呢？
The why look give us good protection?
为什么我们要寻求良好的保护？
But doesn't that cost a lot of cpu cycles since we are constantly pulling?
但是这样做会消耗大量的CPU周期，因为我们不断地进行拉取操作。
Absolutely.
当然可以。
It's inefficiency.
这是低效的。
It's your absolutely correct.
这是完全正确的。
It's inefficient.
这是低效的。
It's correct, but inefficient.
这是正确的，但效率不高。
And from Chad,
来自乍得，
wouldn't this possibly make a finished writers broadcast hit awaiting reader?
这是否可能使得一篇完成的作家广播等待读者的作品受欢迎呢？
First before awaiting reader,
首先，在等待读者之前，
if there was both waiting read as a writer,
如果既有读者等待又有写者等待的情况下，
which means observed ordering priority of writers of writers before readers,
这意味着在读者之前观察到的写者的写入顺序优先级。
this will no longer guarantee the priority order between writers and readers.
这将不再保证写者和读者之间的优先顺序。
If you have only one conditioned variables,
如果你只有一个条件变量，
you are no longer going to be guaranteed this one unnecessary,
你将不再被保证这个不必要的东西。
although it is still,
尽管如此，
II you are not guaranteed readers when you wake up,
当你醒来时，并不能保证有读者。
but still in,
但仍然在进行中，
if you want to proceed,
如果你想继续，
you are the while loop will take care of that.
你可以使用 while 循环来处理这个。
In from the point of view of accessing the database,
从访问数据库的角度来看，
the while loop is going to enforce a priority because a reader,
while循环将强制执行优先级，因为一个读者，
it's going to look whether there are active writers or waiting writers.
它将检查是否有活跃的写者或等待中的写者。
And if they are waiting writers,
如果他们是等待的作家，
it's not going to proceed.
无法继续进行。
Right?
对吗？
So as long as they are waiting writers,
只要他们是等待的写入者，
these wire conditions will ensure that the reader cannot proceed.
这些线路条件将确保读者无法继续操作。
So actually,
实际上，
the priority is still enforced.
优先级仍然得到执行。
Okay?
好的？
The priority is enforced by the while of conditions.
优先级是通过条件的 while 循环来实施的。
But the priority is not enforcing the sense that you can wake
但是优先级不在于强制你能够醒来的感觉。
up every a reader while you shouldn't have woken up.
在你还没有醒来的时候，每个读者都不应该被唤醒。
And this can lead,
这可能会导致，
again to deadlocks without without changing the code and more be
再次讨论死锁问题，不改变代码的情况下，并且更深入地研究。
more liberal in broadcasting the ok continue.
在广播方面更加自由开放，好的，继续。
Okay.
好的。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
And i'll see you on Tuesday and Monday.
我会在周二和周一见到你。
Bye.
再见。